<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Monal</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/</link><description>Recent content on Monal</description><image><url>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/papermod-cover.png</url><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/papermod-cover.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Supported XEPs</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/supportedxeps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 10:19:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/supportedxeps/</guid><description>Implemented XEPs XEP Status Since XEP-0004: Data Forms partial 4.9 XEP-0030: Service Discovery complete 4.6 XEP-0045: Multi-User Chat partial 5.0 XEP-0048: Bookmarks complete 5.0 XEP-0059: Result Set Management. Used by other XEPs. complete 4.8 XEP-0060: Publish-Subscribe partial 4.9 XEP-0066: Out of Band Data partial 4.9 XEP-0077: In-Band Registration partial XEP-0084: User Avatar complete 4.9 XEP-0085: Chat State Notifications complete 4.7 XEP-0092: Software Version complete XEP-0115: Entity Capabilities complete 4.7 XEP-0162: Best Practices for Roster and Subscription Management complete XEP-0163: Personal Eventing Protocol complete 4.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/support/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 10:01:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/support/</guid><description>Monal MUC: monal@chat.yax.im Github Tickets: https://github.com/monal-im/Monal/issues Email: info[at]monal[minus]im[dot]org. Reporting a Vulnerability It is highly appreciated reporting a vulnerability to the Monal developers. We ask you for disclosure until it has been fixed. This prevents abuse and exploitation in the current published releases. Please report issues directly to info[at]monal[minus]im[dot]org.
Please try to report
in detail what you are concerned about if applicable, how to reproduce your contact details, if the sending email is not enough.</description></item><item><title>Donate</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/donate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 09:16:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/donate/</guid><description>Monal is developed by volunteers and community collaboration. The work which has been done is usually not paid, and the developers ask for donations to keep up service costs and development in the future! Please consider giving a little back for the hard work which has been conducted. Currently, there are three ways for financial support of the Monal development:
Donate via GitHub Sponsors Donate via Libera Pay EU citizens can donate via SEPA, too.</description></item><item><title>Install</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/install/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:09:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/install/</guid><description> iOS macOS macOS (homebrew) Stable App Store App Store Beta Testflight Testflight brew install &amp;ndash;cask monal Alpha brew tap monal-im/homebrew-monal-alpha
brew install &amp;ndash;cask monal-alpha Release cycle</description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:08:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/privacy/</guid><description>Monal-im.org (Website) A user’s IP address will be logged in the HTTP server logs. All server logs are purged every two weeks and there isn’t any way for us to associate this information with any particular individual.
Monal (App) Monal for iOS and macOS will register for APNS push notifications via a server to server (s2s) connection from your XMPP server to our push server. Your XMPP JID alongside with a push identifier and secret token from apple, that is only valid for this app, will be saved and logged in the push-server logs.</description></item><item><title>Insights Into Monal Development</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/post/00001-monal-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/post/00001-monal-development/</guid><description>TLDR:
Info: Monal will stop support for iOS 12, iOS 13 and macOS Catalina!
We are searching for a SwiftUI developer.
We need a new simplified website.
With better continuous funding, our push servers will move from the US to Europe.
We have a new support mail: info@monal-im.org
Two years ago we decided to rewrite the Monal app almost entirely and improve it gradually in the process, instead of creating another XMPP Client for iOS and macOS.</description></item><item><title>Monal-IM. Privacy like it's 1999</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/home/</guid><description>Monal is a XMPP instant messaging client for MacOS and iOS which strives to be the go-to client for these platforms just like the app Conversations IM is for Android. XMPP in general is an open and standardized protocol for real time communication. Anyone can host their own server and communicate freely with each other, just like with email and just like email the used addresses are of the form &amp;ldquo;user@domain.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/about/</guid><description>Imprint Thilo Molitor Vogelsbergstr. 18 68642 Bürstadt Germany
eMail: info[at]monal[minus]im[dot]org
About Monal originates in 2002 as fork of the SworIM app. Until 2019 it has been developed by Anu Pokharel. Since then Thilo Molitor took over the development and joined in 2020 with Friedrich Altheide. From initial rewrite of code in the backend the entire app has been upgraded with a modern XMPP engine, new features and future-proof setup. Monal challenges to be the go-to XMPP chat-app for the iOS and macOS platform.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://monal-im.github.io/monal-im.org/features/</guid><description>Monal currently covers the following chat features:
Decentralised and federated chat standard XMPP Private and group messaging Privacy-respecting push notifications Encrypted private and group chats (state-of-the-art encryption (OMEMO)) Message history Free selection of your XMPP account provider Voice messaging Message archiving Upload of files, videos and images (HTTP Upload) Many settings and a design to offer privacy settings in the app to the need of the user A detailed and technical listing of your supported features (so called XMPP Extensions) can be found in our DOAP file.</description></item></channel></rss>